RAJAN

SDE @ KRISHWORKS | MCA - JMI NEW DELHI

ABOUT ME

Software Developer with 1+ year of experience in problem-solving and critical thinking, developing and delivering high-quality software products. Experienced in developing web applications and websites using various technologies such as Reactjs, Node.js, and Django.

8273169008

✓ <u>rkp33510@gmail.com</u>

https://github.com/rajan624

Bengluru India

EDUCATION

WORK EXPERIENCE

Masters Computer Application

July 2019 - Jun 2022

- Jamia Millia Islamia (Central University)
- New Delhi

Post Graduate Diploma in Computer Hardware

July 2017 - Jun 2018

- Govt. Polytechnic Kanpur
- Kanpur

Bachelor Of Science (Mathematics)

July 2013 - Jun 2016

- National Post Graduate college
- Mainpuri UP

SKILLS

- Languages: Java, SQL, JavaScript, HTML/CSS, Python,OOPS
- Frameworks: Reactjs, React-Redux, Nodejs, Express ,MongoDB, Django Rest
 Framework, Django Firebase
- Developer Tools: Git, VS
 Code, Data Structure

CERTIFICATE

Data Structure in Java <u>Link</u>
Front End <u>Link</u>
Back End | Node.js <u>Link</u>
Career Camp | React <u>Link</u>

Krishworks Technology

Software Engineer

Bengaluru Jan 2022 - Present

I built a feature-rich job portal with ReactJS and Firebase, emphasizing user experience and SEO techniques. Additionally, I automated customer relationship management using Django Rest Framework, incorporating RBAC authentication and Stripe for secure subscription payments.

- Developed a comprehensive job portal front-end and backend using ReactJS and Firebase. Enhanced the user experience by implementing SEO techniques. Facilitated subscription payments via Stripe. Achieved a user base of over 5,000+ users.
- Developed CRM Backend system utilizing Django Rest Framework to automate customer relationship management processes. Implemented a RBAC authentication system to ensure data security
- Developed an ecommerce web Front end using ReactJS to enable smooth user experience. Implemented business flow logic to ensure seamless completion of the purchase process.

PROJECTS

@lsearch-Web-App

GitHub

Live

Sep 2021 - Dec 2021

Apr 2023 - Present

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Firebase

- Designed a web application for rapid search of missing children, utilizing HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript and Firebase.
- Developed search functions to allow parents to easily find their children. Optimized the application for seamless and efficient performance

Reactjs, Nodejs, Express, MongoDB

CMS-Web-App FrontEnd Backend

- Designed a user-friendly interface for creating and managing blog posts within the web app.
- Successfully achieved the objective of creating a MERN content management web app with user authentication, blog creation and management, follower system, and messaging functionality.
- Designed a user-friendly interface for creating and managing blog posts within the web app